Caleb Welch

Boston, MA

Phone: (603)-680-5423 | Email: calebwelch.design@gmail.com

Driven developer who is always learning. Experienced in building client facing, fully custom applications with typescript, javascript, CSS, SCSS and Nodejs in an Agile Development system. Creates cloud solutions with in-depth AWS knowledge.

#Skills

Front-End	Back End	Source Control	FrameWorks	UI/UX
Javascript ES6 / jQuery	REST / MySQL	Git(Git Flow)	React / Redux	Wireframing
TypeScript	GraphQL	Github Issues	Vue3	Figma
CSS / SASS / LESS	NodeJS	SCRUM / Agile	AngularJS	Prototyping
HTML / XHTML	End to End Testing	Github	Bootstrap	Adobe Suite
Webpack		Jira / Bitbucket	Cloud	User Stories
508 Accessibility			AWS	Atomic Design

#Professional Experience

Genetesis / Software Engineer II

November 2020 - Current: Mason, OH

- Developed and refactored 3 applications met FDA medical device verification requirements and subsequently helped pass medical trials and close a series C funding.
- Optimized and secured client authentication utilizing Vuex, GraphQL and AWS.
- Developed an internal Research and Development App with complex interactive D3 graphs.
- Overhauled the entire company UI and UX including 4 applications with 70 client facing components and over 110+ unique iterations creating a modern and functional look to display vital medical information.
- Developed and optimized UI/UX for over 30 client facing application pages for displaying and interacting with patient information and the Cardioflux device.
- Built client side pdf rendering application from scratch and designed a for print dynamic medical report.
- Utilized SCSS, CSS, SASS, Tailwind, transparent wrappers, and modern css architecture to create custom components.
- Diagnose and resolve company tech-debt including updating over 60 packages across 4 repositories.
- Update all company applications for accessibility meeting ARIA WCAG 2.2 guidelines
- Wrote documentation for an FDA De Novo Classification Request.

Known Point Technologies / Full Stack Software Engineer Intern

September 2020 - November 2020: Concord, NH

• Built a clean front end UI for customer onboarding and deployed Lambda functions to AWS

#Education

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate / 2023 / Credential ID: NMH5PE92TF1EQ535 **AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner** / 2022 / Credential ID: F1Q322QKRN1EQGWK **University of New Hampshire** / **Certificate in Full Stack Web Development**

March 2020 - September 2020: Durham NH

Boston College/ B.A Psychology

August 2013 - May 2017 : Chestnut Hill